barn2.co.uk 2018-11-20

# Privacy Policy

## Who we are

We are Barn2 Media. Our website address is: https://barn2.co.uk.

Our legal business name: Barn2 Media Limited  
Our company registration number: 08565444  
Our VAT number: GB188117584  
Our office address: Tuckers Brook House, Modbury, Ivybridge, Devon, PL21 0UT, United Kingdom

We don’t provide a phone number for contact, as we are an [email only](https://barn2.co.uk/email-support-is-best/) company. But feel free to email us anytime – info [at] barn2.co.uk – or send us a message via our [contact page](https://barn2.co.uk/contact-a-wordpress-designer/).

## What personal data we collect and why we collect it

When visitors leave comments on the site we collect the data shown in the comments form, and also the visitor’s IP address and browser user agent string to help with spam detection.

An anonymized string created from your email address (also called a hash) may be provided to the Gravatar service to see if you are using it. The Gravatar service privacy policy is available here: https://automattic.com/privacy/. After approval of your comment, your profile picture is visible to the public in the context of your comment, as well as the name you provided. Your email address is never displayed.

### Contact forms

We have a number of contact forms, including our [main contact form](https://barn2.co.uk/contact-a-wordpress-designer/) and our [plugin support form.](https://barn2.co.uk/our-wordpress-plugins/plugin-support-request/) When visitors contact us via one of these forms, we collect the data shown in the form as well as the visitor’s IP address.

We use this information to reply to you regarding your enquiry, to provide you with a quote, or to provide support for our plugin. We do not share this information with third parties or use it for marketing purposes. The data stored from the contact forms is deleted after 1 year.

### Plugin purchases

We collect information about you when you purchase a plugin from our store. This information includes your name, email address, billing address, payment method and IP address. If you provide a VAT number, we also store this as well as the associated business name and address.

Storing this data also allows us to:

  * Send you your order receipt and plugin download link.
  * Send you important account/service information.
  * Respond to your queries, refund requests, or complaints.
  * Process payments and to prevent fraudulent transactions. We do this on the basis of our legitimate business interests.
  * Set up and administer your account, provide technical and/or customer support, and to verify your identity.

Please note that we do not store any payment information or credit card details on our website. If you purchase using PayPal then your payment is securely handled by them. If you pay by credit card, then your credit card details are securely processed by [Stripe](https://stripe.com/gb), who provide our payment processing facility. You can read [Stripe’s Privacy Policy](https://stripe.com/gb/privacy) and [PayPal Privacy Policy](https://www.paypal.com/en/webapps/mpp/ua/privacy-full) for more information.

When you visit any plugin page, we use your IP address to determine your local currency in order to set the correct price for that plugin.

When you purchase a plugin, an account will be created for you automatically. A secure password is randomly generated and linked to the email address you provided during checkout. This information will be emailed to you so you can login to your account in future. You can use your account to view your purchase history, access downloads, and generate invoices.

If you leave a plugin review, we store the information entered in the review form for the purposes of displaying the review on the relevant plugin page. We display your name and review on the website, but not your email address. If your email address is associated with a Gravatar (see Comments above), we will display your Gravatar profile picture next to the review.

### Web design and hosting

We store information about you when you use any of our web design services, including MySimpleSite, MySimpleStore, website hosting, and ongoing support services. The information we store is limited to the data provided by you to us, such as your name, email address, postal address and phone number. We store some of this information in our accounting system for the purposes of billing the supplied services.

### Cookies

If you leave a comment on our site you may opt-in to saving your name, email address and website in cookies. These are for your convenience so that you do not have to fill in your details again when you leave another comment. These cookies will last for one year.

If you have an account and you log in to this site, we will set a temporary cookie to determine if your browser accepts cookies. This cookie contains no personal data and is discarded when you close your browser.

When you log in, we will also set up several cookies to save your login information and your screen display choices. Login cookies last for two days, and screen options cookies last for a year. If you select “Remember Me”, your login will persist for two weeks. If you log out of your account, the login cookies will be removed.

If you edit or publish an article, an additional cookie will be saved in your browser. This cookie includes no personal data and simply indicates the post ID of the article you just edited. It expires after 1 day.

If you visit one of our plugin pages then we set a cookie which contains your local currency (e.g. “USD” for US Dollars). We also set a cookie which stores your country code (e.g. “US” for United States) which we use to determine the payment options available to you on checkout. Both of these cookies expire after 1 day.

Certain plugin pages and blog articles show a small pop-up box in the bottom right-hand corner, asking if you would like to sign up to a newsletter. We set a cookie when this box is closed, so we can prevent it being displayed again. This cookie expires after 1 day.

If you start the purchase of a plugin we set a cookie which contains the number of items currently in your cart (e.g. “1”).

### Embedded content from other websites

Articles on this site may include embedded content (e.g. videos, images, articles, etc.). Embedded content from other websites behaves in the exact same way as if the visitor has visited the other website.

These websites may collect data about you, use cookies, embed additional third-party tracking, and monitor your interaction with that embedded content, including tracing your interaction with the embedded content if you have an account and are logged in to that website.

### Analytics

We use Google Analytics to collect anonymous statistics about our visitors. This information includes, but is not limited to, the browser and operating system that was used, the visitor’s location, the pages visited during a given session, the date and time of the visit, and the page that was visited before arriving on our website (the referring page). If you purchase a plugin from our store, we record the value of the transaction in Google Analytics.

We use this information to analyze visitor and customer behaviour, to identify sources of website traffic, and make improvements to our website and plugin store.

We do not use any of the Advertising Features provided by Google Analytics.

The Google Analytics service will set up to 3 cookies in your browser. Two are used to uniquely identify you (to distinguish one visitor from another). These expire after 1 day and 2 years respectively. The third cookie is used to throttle the request rate, and expires after 1 minute.

If you signup to one of our newsletters, or purchase a plugin from us, we store your name and email address in [MailChimp](https://mailchimp.com/features/landing-pages/). MailChimp provide our newsletter service to send the emails you have requested, or to send you updates about our plugins. You can unsubscribe from these at any time.

When you start the process of purchasing one of our plugins but do not complete the purchase, we store your name, email address, and billing address (if provided) in [Jilt](https://jilt.com/). Jilt provide a service to recover ‘abandoned carts’, where a customer has started a purchase but has not yet completed it. Jilt use the information we provide to send you an email to ask if you would like to complete your purchase.

## How long we retain your data

If you leave a comment, the comment and its metadata are retained indefinitely. This is so we can recognize and approve any follow-up comments automatically instead of holding them in a moderation queue.

For users that register on our website (if any), we also store the personal information they provide in their user profile. All users can see, edit, or delete their personal information at any time (except they cannot change their username). Website administrators can also see and edit that information.

If you send us a message or support request via one of our contact forms, this information will be held for 1 year.

If you purchase a plugin from us, the order and customer details are retained indefinitely. This is for tax, accounting and reporting. Your user account (created automatically during checkout) is also stored indefinitely. Please contact us if you would like to delete your account.

If you are one of our web design or web hosting clients, we hold the information you have provided to us for as long as you are a client. If you are no longer one of our clients, we archive and subsequently delete your information.

## What rights you have over your data

If you have an account on this site, or have left comments, you can request to receive an exported file of the personal data we hold about you, including any data you have provided to us. You can also request that we erase any personal data we hold about you. This does not include any data we are obliged to keep for administrative, legal, or security purposes.

## Where we send your data

Visitor comments may be checked through an automated spam detection service.

If you have any queries about this privacy policy, any privacy-specific concerns, would like to submit a data access request or data removal request, please get in touch with us via our [contact form](https://barn2.co.uk/contact-a-wordpress-designer/) or email us: privacy [at] barn2.co.uk.
